<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>Knight-Mozilla OpenNews</title>
<description>The blog for the Knight-Mozilla OpenNews project</description>
<link>http://www.opennews.org</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.opennews.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>SRCCON sessions</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>&lt;p&gt;SRCCON is an event centered around experiences. We strive to create a space where people can explore and build connections, and the core of that is the slate of pre-planned sessions. The sessions don&amp;rsquo;t just create a schedule for SRCCON, they shape the event itself as a third of participants are also session facilitators and their sessions spill over into hallyway and evening conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenNews as an organization is structured in a way to be able to respond to the &lt;a href=&quot;jobs&quot;&gt;needs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;events&quot;&gt;interests&lt;/a&gt; of the community, and create spaces to &lt;a href=&quot;source&quot;&gt;celebrate&lt;/a&gt; its work. We aim to imbue SRCCON with these same goals. So the first and most important part of that is making sure as much of the community as possible is represented at SRCCON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a &lt;a href=&quot;tickets&quot;&gt;small event&lt;/a&gt;, it means that entire community can&amp;rsquo;t be physically present at SRCCON, but through session proposals we were able to encourage a wide swath of that community to describe what they were interested in sharing. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll review some of our strategies related to session proposal outreach and selection as well as some of the themes we noticed in reviewing sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OUTREACH&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we began planning SRCCON, we decided that the entire session proposal, review, and selection process would happen before tickets went on sale. We also decided that anyone whose proposal we accepted, we would reserve a ticket for that person. We suspected SRCCON would sell out quickly again this year (and &lt;a href=&quot;tweet&quot;&gt;it did&lt;/a&gt;), so that meant that encouraging people to propose sessions was the best way to make sure their interests were represented in the schedule and give them the best chance at getting a ticket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how did we make sure people knew about the SRCCON call for proposals? We did a lot of outreach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building out existing channels - we encouraged people through our existing channels. Twitter, email lists, our &lt;a href=&quot;call&quot;&gt;community call&lt;/a&gt;, and through more extensive blogging on OpenNews.org than we have done in the past. We kept momentum going by starting the &lt;a href=&quot;docs&quot;&gt;documentation train&lt;/a&gt; for SRCCON as well as posting a couple of pieces about proposal writing: &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;How to plan a great SRCCON session&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Five things we&amp;rsquo;ve learned about sessions&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reaching out to existing networks - we did a lot of brainstorming. We gathered lists of Source writers, community call participants, fellowship alumni, and fellowship partners. We also thought about people we had connected with in the last year or whose pitches we just couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connecting with groups we wanted to make sure were well represented - we put an emphasis in our individual outreach on people from small and non-coastal newsrooms, people of color, and women. In addition, we wanted to make sure the perspective of locals would be evident throughout SRCCON, so we sought out recommendations of people in Minneapolis/St. Paul to invite to propose sessions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Beyond emails and tweets, we hosted a &lt;a href=&quot;link&quot;&gt;question and answer session&lt;/a&gt; on our community call, had open office hours, and fielded individual questions via email. We wanted to make sure that if someone was interested in pitching a proposal, they would have the support they needed to do that. We view facilitating a session as a great way to share and become more connected with peers in this community, so we wanted everyone to feel able to take that step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SESSION PROPOSAL FORM
We reviewed our session proposal form from last year and discussed making adjustments to make it even easier for people to share session ideas. Some changes we made included:
* Asking people if they needed a co-facilitator and offering to help find one - sometimes it can be really stressful to have an idea and want to pitch it and not know quite who to pitch it with. We wanted to take that pressure off.
* We changed up the session length question - rather than two options, we encouraged 1 hour sessions, with the opportunity for people to describe how a session would work in a shorter or longer format. We wanted people to be able to pitch an idea that could go a few different ways and not stress about making sure it would work in an hour, or else!
* We listed different types of session formats - especially since SRCCON is a different type of conference than many, we wanted to make sure people had an idea of the different formats we&amp;rsquo;ve seen work well for sessions. People could select any or all options, and since we&amp;rsquo;ll be offering facilitation support leading up to the event, we asked people what we could do to help make their session awesome as well.
* We asked ahead of time if people would be ok merging sessions - last year we saw a lot of session proposals on similar topics and asked session facilitators if they would work together as part of the session acceptance process. This year, we wanted to make sure we asked beforehand&amp;ndash;both as a heads up and so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t plan to merge someone who didn&amp;rsquo;t want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also made one major change to the form that was for our own accountability&amp;ndash;we asked people an optional question: Do you identify as (multiple select option) a woman, person of color, or member of another underrepresented group in technology? We wanted to make sure that session facilitators represented the diversity of communities we serve, and this question allowed us to track our efforts there based on self-reported information rather than gut feelings or guesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;REVIEWING THE SESSIONS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year we got 126 session proposals and accepted 46. It was an extremely challenging selection process. Since last year was the first SRCCON, we got a big range of session proposals and a lot of them didn&amp;rsquo;t quite fit what we were hoping to do at SRCCON. But this year, wow. People really took to heart what we wrote about and the experiences they heard participants had last year. Some trends jumped out at us right away:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ton of co-facilitated sessions - some sessions were pitched by one person, but the majority of sessions had a co-facilitator or were interested in finding one. This seemed to really reflect an interest in collaborative, interactive sessions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A ton of culture sessions - because we are vocal about &lt;a href=&quot;doclink&quot;&gt;intentionality and consideration&lt;/a&gt;, we heard from so many people who were interested in talking about culture and how we work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diversity in so many ways - fewer than half the sessions proposed had only white guys listed as facilitators. The mix of facilitators and co-facilitators on sessions often showed different genders, races, backgrounds, and experiences. Within and outside of their own organization, people sought out co-facilitators to bring a different perspective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We split up the actual review process into a few different stages. All OpenNews staff did a first pass, logging impressions and doing a first ranking. From there, the staff discussed ideas and questions to take into the next round of review. At the same time, we invited a small number of community numbers to review the sessions and share their 5 favorite sessions. We selected a group to represent a range of different backgrounds and news organization types.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan Pitts and I did a more granular review. Testing the limits of our understanding of Screendoor, we tagged sessions for topic area, style, and ranking by the community reviewers, and we diligently (but quickly, we gave ourselves just less than two weeks for the entire review process) got to a list of sessions to suggest we accept. We discussed those recommendations again as a staff and came up with a list of accepted sessions, including a few mergers and a small list of sessions we were still thinking about how to involve outside of the official schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, we crafted a mix of hands-on and discussion oriented sessions, some culture and some code, a range of different topics, and a list of sessions that showcases the brilliance of 70 community members.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LOOKING AHEAD&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In thinking about sessions for this year, we referred back to feedback from participants at the first SRCCON. That led to us changing the suggested length of sessions and helped us understand the parts of sessions people really value. Already we have some inklings on feedback for us to consider for next year. The volume of amazing session proposals has challenged us to think about are there other ways for us to support discussions of culture or journalism education? Could that somehow be related to SRCCON itself or happen at other times during the year? We&amp;rsquo;re really interested in &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:srccon@opennews.org&quot;&gt;talking more about this&lt;/a&gt; and hearing any suggestions you may have. We&amp;rsquo;re also excited about continued experimentation about session types and styles during SRCCON, or ways for other organizations to using SRCCON as a jumping off point for their own programming, in Minneapolis and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all of the people who took the time to submit a session proposal and of course to the folks who will be facilitating sessions at SRCCON. We&amp;rsquo;ll post plenty of documentation of the sessions themselves and look forward to continuing to evolve our official program next year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>

<pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-sessions</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-sessions</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Meet the projects coming to Code Convening&amp;#58; Write The Docs</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Meet the seven projects we're bringing to our code convening at Write The Docs 2015.</description>

<pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/code-convening-portland</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/code-convening-portland</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>SRCCON Ticketing—What We Did and Why</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>This year, as we prepare for SRCCON 2015, we're making an effort to document our work in public as we go. This post on our ticketing process will be followed shortly by one on session selection, with more to come between now and the end of June.</description>

<pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-tickets</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-tickets</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Coral Project is Go Go Go Go Go</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Exciting things are happening at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/coralproject&quot;&gt;The Coral Project&lt;/a&gt; and we thought you should know about them.</description>

<pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 12:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/coral-andrew</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/coral-andrew</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Five Reasons You Shouldn't Come to SRCCON (and Why They're All Wrong)</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Tickets to &lt;a href=&quot;http://srccon.org/&quot;&gt;SRCCON, the OpenNews conference&lt;/a&gt;, go on sale Wednesday, April 29 at 2pm EDT. But maybe you're still on the fence about SRCCON, or are worried that you won't quite fit in. If so, worry no longer—instead, check out our five top reasons why you shouldn't come to SRCCON (and why they're all wrong).</description>

<pubDate>Wed, 22 Apr 2015 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srcconqs</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srcconqs</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Code Convening&amp;#58; Write The Docs. Come open your code with us!</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>We'll be taking a cohort of news developers and journalists to the Write The Docs conference, May 17-19 in Portland, to write and revise documentation, release the latest version of their open-source projects, and talk journalism with the technical documentation community.</description>

<pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2015 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/code-convening-wtd</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/code-convening-wtd</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Five Things We've Learned About Sessions</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>As we near the deadline for SRCCON session proposals (April 10, &lt;a href=&quot;http://srccon.org/sessions&quot;&gt;pitch now&lt;/a&gt;) we wanted to share with you some of what we've learned about sessions so far. Thank you to everyone who shared feedback about last year's conference and helped inform &lt;a href=&quot;http://opennews.org/blog/srccon-human-stuff&quot;&gt;how we're thinking about things&lt;/a&gt; this year.</description>

<pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-top5</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-top5</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>How to plan a great SRCCON session</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>SRCCON sessions are interactive and collaborative, and if you've never led one, it can be hard to know what to expect. Here are some strategies to help you lead a discussion or skillshare that gets everyone involved and leaves everyone energized.</description>

<pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-session-planning</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-session-planning</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Captioning a Multi-Track Conference - How SRCCON Did It</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>One of the nerdiest elements of our first SRCCON didn't end up involving code or jokey references. As we were prepping for SRCCON last year, I caught a blog post related to !!Con, &lt;a href=&quot;http://composition.al/blog/2014/05/31/your-next-conference-should-have-real-time-captioning/&quot;&gt;Your next conference should have real-time captioning&lt;/a&gt;. I had never heard of event captioning before. I found the blog post convincing, but we were less than two months away from SRCCON, could we pull off something like this?</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-transcription</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-transcription</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hosting a Knight-Mozilla Fellow in 2016</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Next year will be the fifth year of the Knight-Mozilla Fellowship program and we're looking for our next group of fellowship partners. If your news organization is interested in hosting a fellow next year, &lt;a href=&quot;http://opennews.org/what/fellowships/partnerguidelines/#form&quot;&gt;fill out this form&lt;/a&gt; by April 24.</description>

<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2015 16:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/fellowship-2016-partner</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/fellowship-2016-partner</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
