<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>Knight-Mozilla OpenNews</title>
<description>The blog for the Knight-Mozilla OpenNews project</description>
<link>http://www.opennews.org</link>
<atom:link href="http://www.opennews.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Thursday Nights at SRCCON</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Our evening program at SRCCON is designed to offer the &quot;life&quot; part of the work/life balance. We've iterated on it every year--here's how we did it this year.</description>

<pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 11:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-thursday</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-thursday</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>How We Planned &amp; Ran the SRCCON Travel Scholarships</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>One part of how we make SRCCON accessible is through travel scholarships. This is how we administer the program.</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-scholarship-process-admin</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-scholarship-process-admin</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>How We Facilitated a Huge, Participatory, Highly Charged SRCCON Session, a Guest Post from Alyson Hurt</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>As the SRCCON organizers reminded us, our job was to *facilitate* a session, and our topic in particular felt like it was meant to be a conversation (rather than, say, a skill-share or lesson). We had some thoughts and past experience to share, but we by no means considered ourselves experts. In a group setting, we could all learn from *each other* about ways—as individuals, as managers, as teams, as organizations—folks are dealing with burnout and job satisfaction now, and maybe devise new strategies to try in the future.</description>

<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-facilitator-recs-two</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-facilitator-recs-two</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>3 Ways to Facilitate a Great Conference Session, a Guest Post from Sisi Wei</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>If you've never presented at a conference with facilitators instead of speakers before, you're in for a treat. Facilitation is a much more interactive way of running sessions at conferences, and when done well, both the facilitator and the attendees walk away feeling inspired, motivated, and like they've learned a lot from everyone in the room.</description>

<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-facilitator-recs-one</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-facilitator-recs-one</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Importance of Presence - Announcing a New Way to Connect</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>We want to help you get to events that will enrich your work in the journalism code community. Today we announce a Ticket and Travel scholarship program.</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/ticket-travel-scholarship</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/ticket-travel-scholarship</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Gone in 60 Seconds--SRCCON Ticketing Changes</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Ticket sales for SRCCON are coming soon and we're making some changes to how we sell them this year.</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 12:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-tix</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/srccon-tix</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why You Should Pitch a SRCCON Session (Today)</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Every year, the SRCCON proposal deadline comes up faster than seems possible, but it's not yet too late—in fact, this is the perfect time to submit your pitch.</description>

<pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2016 14:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/why-pitch-srccon</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/why-pitch-srccon</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tools, Bridges, and Five Years of Knight-Mozilla Fellows</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Today's announcement of our 2016 Knight-Mozilla Fellows adds a fifth cohort to our fellowship community.</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 14:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/five-years-of-fellows</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/five-years-of-fellows</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Introducing our 2016 Knight-Mozilla Fellows</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Today we get to announce our fifth cohort of fellows, and tell a little about how we found them.</description>

<pubDate>Thu, 05 Nov 2015 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/introducing-2016-fellows</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/introducing-2016-fellows</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>The &amp;#40;remarkably consistent&amp;#41; Data-Driven Decisions of the Final Day of Fellowship Applications</title>
<dc:creator></dc:creator>

<description>Today is the final day to apply to become a 2016 Knight-Mozilla Fellow. After more than two months, these last few hours are all that's left. We crunch the numbers to see what previous last days have looked like and to let you know that you're not alone in waiting to today.</description>

<pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 09:26:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://www.opennews.org/blog/fellowships-final-week-itsover</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.opennews.org/blog/fellowships-final-week-itsover</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
